Guide to the Paul D. Carrington Papers, 1985-2013 UA.20.02.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Paul D. Carrington papers
1985-2013
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Carrington, Paul D., 1931-
UA.20.02.0001
4.5 Linear Feet
Paul D. Carrington was Dean of the Law School at Duke University and is Professor Emeritus. The collection contains materials primarily from Paul Carrington's time as Professor Emeritus at the Duke Law School and include correspondence and research materials on his writings on legal and judicial reform.
Biographical / Historical
Paul D. Carrington was Dean of the Law School at Duke University and is Professor Emeritus.
Paul Carrington was born June 12, 1931, in Dallas, Texas, and attended the University of Texas (1952) and Harvard Law School (LL.B., 1955). He served in the Army until 1957, when he became a teaching fellow at Harvard Law School until 1958. He then became a Assistant Professor of Law at the University of Wyoming until 1960, when he moved to the Indiana University School of Law. In 1962 he became Associate Professor of Law at Ohio State University, moving to the University of Michigan Law School as Professor of Law in 1965. In 1978, he was named Dean of the School of Law at Duke University.
During his time as Dean of the Law School, Professor Carrington helped establish the Richard M. Nixon Scholarship Program which funded the study of Chinese students and scholars at Duke Law in the 1980s and 1990s, and which later evolved into the Global Leader Scholarship. When he stepped down as dean in 1988, he became the Harry R. Chadwick, Sr. Professor Emeritus of Law and continued to teach.
In his teaching, research, and writings, Carrington has focused on a wide variety of legal subjects, including legal reform, legal education, civil procedure, contracts, constitutional law, and the history of the legal profession. He has published numerous books, articles, and opinion pieces, including Stewards of Democracy (1999) and Reforming the Supreme Court: Term Limits for Justices (edited with Roger C. Cramton, 2006). He served as Reporter to the Advisory Committee on Civil Rules of the Judicial Conference of the United States from 1985-1992, and is an elected member of the American Law Institute, an elected Fellow of the American Bar Foundation, an elected Fellow of the American Academy of Arts & Sciences, and an Honorary Fellow of the American Academy of Appellate Lawyers.
Sources: Paul D. Carrington's faculty profile for Duke Law, https://law.duke.edu/fac/carrington/; faculty profile at the University of Michigan School of Law, https://www.law.umich.edu/historyandtraditions/faculty/Faculty_Lists/Alpha_Faculty/Pages/PaulDCarrington.aspx; both viewed February 16, 2017.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Paul D. Carrington Papers were received by the Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2016.
Related Materials
School of Law Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
School of Law Reference Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Carrington, Paul D. Papers, 1968-1993, Harvard Law School Library, Harvard Library, Harvard University.
Collection Overview
The collection contains materials primarily from Paul Carrington's time as Professor Emeritus at the Duke Law School. Included is correspondence on a number of legal issues, research materials, teaching and class materials, newsclippings, and other materials. Topics covered include judicial independence, judicial and legal refrom, legal education, Paul Carrington's writings, and other subjects.
Law -- Study and teaching -- United States; Judicial independence; Law reform -- United States; Duke University. School of Law; Carrington, Paul D., 1931-
- Correspondence on Writings, 1985; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Press Clippings State Judicial Elections vol. 1 of 3: Alabama-Washington, 1998; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Press Clippings State Judicial Elections vol. 2 of 3: District of Columbia and Miscellaneous, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
- Press Clippings State Judicial Elections vol. 3 of 3: Texas, 1989-1999; 2 folders (Box 1)
- PAC: Science and Law, 1995-2002 (Box 1)
- PDC: Correspondence with Justices, 1997-2006 (Box 1)
- 2F3 Jury Delay, 1996-2013; 3 folders (Box 1)
- Appeals, 1992-2010 (Box 1)
- Public Education and Local Government: Durham, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
- re: History of Legal Education, 1993-2010; 3 folders (Box 1)
- PDC: Duke Law Alumni and Colleges, 1990-2010 (Box 1)
- Class [title unknown], 1997-2002; 2 folders (Box 1)
- PDC: re: Laws and Science, 1996-2002 (Box 1)
- PDC Correspondence re: War on Drugs, 1994-2009 (Box 2)
- Judicial Independent State Courts, 1997-2008 (Box 2)
- Supreme Court, 1998-2012 (Box 2)
- Judging Science, 1993-2003 (Box 2)
- re: President's Day, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
- PAC: [title unknown], 1986-1990 (Box 2)
- Fair Bargains Legislation, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1993-2007 (Box 2)
- re: Judicial Elections not NC, 1997-2008 (Box 2)
- NC Bar Association Judicial Independence Committee, 1998-2007 (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Japan and China, 1994-2007 (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Germany, 1996-2013 (Box 2)
- AKE, 1974 (Box 2)
- AARP, 2003-2008 (Box 2)
- International Correspondence Misc., 2002-2007 (Box 2)
- Terrorism, 1997-2002 (Box 2)
- Stewards of Democracy, 1998-2009 (Box 2)
- False Claims Laws, 2000-2011 (Box 2)
- Federal Rules of Civic Procedure, 1997-2013 (Box 2)
- re: NC Judicial Law Reform, 1997-2008; 2 folders (Box 2)
- re: 2004 Campaign NC Senate (Box 2)
- Federal Rules of Civic Procedure, 1988-2004; 3 folders (Box 2)
- re: Supreme Court Reform, 2004-2009 (Box 2)
- International Corruption, 2008-2010 (Box 2)
- International Litigation, 1996-2011 (Box 2)
- PDC License, 2000 (Box 2)
- Comparative Civic Procedure, 1994-2009 (Box 2)
- PDC Harvard Classmates and Colleagues, 1996-2012 (Box 3)
- Law Colleagues, 1999-2007 (Box 3)
- Former Colleagues/Michigan, 1990-2010 (Box 3)
- Exeter Classmates, 1990-2010 (Box 3)
- Texas [connections?], 1990-2010 (Box 3)
- Management, 1995-1998; 2 folders (Box 3)
- PAC Management, 1999-2003 (Box 3)
- PAC Management, 1991-1994 (Box 3)
- International Commerce, 1996-1999 (Box 3)
- PAC Smith Barney vs. Martens, 1998 (Box 3)
- PAC re: Dalkon Shield, 1994-2013 (Box 3)
- PAC re: Registry of Scientists, 1997-2001 (Box 3)
- PDC re: State's Law of Contracts, re: Arbitration, 2000-2003; 2 folders (Box 3)
- PDC Fair Arbitration Act, 2001-2009 (Box 3)
- re: ABA Philadelphia Conference, re: Judicial Independence, 1998 (Box 3)
- PAC re: Judicial Education, 1995-2001 (Box 3)
- Correspondence to NC Congress and Senators, 1999-2012 (Box 3)
- Citizens for Independent Courts, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
- Public Citizen re: Judicial Elections, 1997 (Box 3)
- PDC re: Federal Jurisdiction, 1994-2002 (Box 3)
- PDC re: Clinton's Impeachment, 1998 (Box 3)
- PDC re: Translyvania Law School, 1991 (Box 3)
- PDC re: Legal Ethics, 2000-2012 (Box 3)